Episode 13
에피소드 13
Taste this.
이것을 맛보세요.
I'm full. You need to eat too.
나는 배불러요. 너도 먹어야 해.
ma'am...
부인...
Something happened to Young Master Hua.
Hua Young Master에게 무슨 일이 일어났습니다.
I eat too much.
나는 너무 많이 먹는다.
Excuse me for a moment.
잠시 실례합니다.
Why did he leave?
그는 왜 떠났나요?
That's not important. You guys just keep going.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다. 너희들은 그냥 계속하세요.
Stay here and watch it all.
여기에 머물면서 모든 것을 지켜보세요.
- Why did you leave? - What happen?
- 왜 떠났나요? - 무슨 일이에요?
It is nothing. Keep eating and drinking.
아무것도 아니다. 계속 먹고 마시세요.
Please bring another bottle of wine.
와인 한 병 더 가져오세요.
Let's move on.
계속 진행합시다.
What did my brother do this time?
내 동생은 이번에 무엇을 했나요?
Currently, Master Hwayoung...
현재 화영스승님...
It was in Concubine Mu's room.
후궁 무의 방에 있었다.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
I don't know exactly.
나는 정확히 모른다.
The waiter came to report...
웨이터가 보고하러 왔는데..
Master Hwayoung infiltrated...
그 화영사부가 잠입했는데...
To the room of Concubine Wu.
무후궁의 방으로.
Sister, wake up.
언니, 일어나세요.
Check out Mu Yao.
무야오를 확인해보세요.
sisters.
자매.
Concubine Mu.
첩 무.
wake up.
깨우다.
sisters!
자매!
Kian.
키안.
blood.
피.
What happen?
무슨 일이에요?
Yao.
야오.
are you okay?
괜찮아?
Tuan.
투안.
I'm doing great.
잘 지내요.
Fortunately, Jisoo arrived on time...
다행히 지수는 시간에 맞춰 도착했어요...
but...
하지만...
By mistake, Young Master Hua was injured.
실수로 Hua Young Master가 부상을 입었습니다.
- teacher.
- 선생님.
Calm down and listen to me.
진정하고 내 말을 들어보세요.
ma'am.
부인.
ma'am!
부인!
Is your wife okay?
부인은 괜찮으세요?
Please show me your hands.
손 좀 보여주세요.
My hands are bleeding.
손에서 피가 나고 있습니다.
Huarongzhou.
화룽저우.
- teacher. - Back off!
- 선생님. - 물러나 다!
Sir, please listen to me.
선생님, 제 말을 들어보세요.
calm down. Let’s find out more...
진정하세요. 더 자세히 알아봅시다...
Before doing something irreversible .
돌이킬 수 없는 일을 하기 전에 .
Please don't disturb me.
방해하지 마십시오.
Sir, don't kill him first.
선생님, 그 사람을 먼저 죽이지 마세요.
How about we find out what's going on?
무슨 일인지 알아보는 게 어때요 ?
Before punishing him?
그를 처벌하기 전에?
Let's find out what happened?
무슨 일이 일어났는지 알아볼까요?
Do you really not understand your brother’s personality?
형의 성격을 정말 이해하지 못하시나요 ?
No wonder you asked His Majesty...
폐하께 물어보신 것도 당연합니다...
So I make Mu Yao my concubine.
그래서 나는 Mu Yao를 내 첩으로 만듭니다.
It seems...
것 같다...
You and your brother have been planning this all along!
당신과 당신의 형제는 이 일을 내내 계획해 왔습니다!
I know I lied to you many times ...
내가 당신에게 여러 번 거짓말을 했다는 걸 알아요 ...
So I don't blame you for not trusting me now.
그러니 지금 나를 믿지 않는다고 해서 당신을 비난하지는 않습니다.
But these are two different things.
그러나 이것은 두 가지 다른 것입니다.
- Sir, calm down... - I won't kill you...
- 선생님, 진정하세요... - 죽이진 않겠습니다...
But I'm going to cripple his arm...
하지만 내가 그 사람 팔을 불구로 만들 거야...
So that he can learn to take care of his hands!
그가 손을 돌보는 법을 배울 수 있도록 !
Kian.
키안.
Save me, Chen.
구해줘, 첸.
Aren't you moving?
이사 안 가시나요?
Kian.
키안.
Calm down, senior.
진정하세요, 선배.
Looks like you want to fight me too.
너도 나와 싸우고 싶어하는 것 같구나.
What does mudamuda mean?
무다무다은 무슨 뜻인가요?
Are you defending this useless person?
이 쓸모없는 사람을 변호하는 겁니까?
Hua Shen was the only son of Chief Steward Hua.
Hua Shen은 Hua 수석 청지기의 외아들이었습니다.
I understand how you feel, sir.
선배님 심정 이해합니다.
However, be reasonable.
하지만, 합리적이어야 합니다.
He treated my girl rudely today.
그는 오늘 내 여자를 무례하게 대했습니다.
It means that the person may be avoiding responsibility...
그 사람이 책임을 회피할 수도 있다는 뜻이군요 ...
Who is that person?
그 사람은 누구입니까?
I'm not defending him.
나는 그를 변호하는 것이 아닙니다.
I think it's better...
제 생각에는 그게 더 나은 것 같아요...
Put that person in jail first...
그 사람을 먼저 감옥에 가두세요...
And wait until Judge Wang investigates.
그리고 왕 판사가 조사할 때까지 기다리세요.
There are more important things to do today.
오늘 해야 할 더 중요한 일이 있습니다 .
Page...
페이지...
Judge Wang will not protect Hua Shen...
왕 판사는 Hua Shen을 보호하지 않을 것입니다 ...
If you see him.
당신이 그를 본다면.
He got away easily.
그는 쉽게 도망갔습니다.
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
Where will you take me?
나를 어디로 데려가시겠어요?
Please help me, Qian.
도와주세요, 퀴안.
Thank you to Teacher Young for your help.
도움주신 영선생님께 감사드립니다.
Go back home...
집으로 돌아가세요...
And treat your wounds.
그리고 상처를 치료하세요.
But there were many people in the front yard.
그런데 앞마당에는 사람이 많았다 .
Leave it to me.
나에게 맡겨.
Take a break and come back again.
잠시 쉬었다가 다시 오세요.
See you again, Young Master.
또 뵙겠습니다, 영 마스터님.
ma'am.
부인.
are you okay?
괜찮아?
I'm doing great.
잘 지내요.
Please forgive.
용서 해줘.
Madam, I'm sorry.
부인, 죄송해요.
There is no need to apologize.
사과할 필요는 없습니다.
good job. I have to thank you.
잘했어요. 나는 당신에게 감사해야합니다.
It doesn't seem weak.
약한 것 같지는 않네요.
thank you.
감사해요.
See a therapist later.
나중에 치료사를 만나십시오.
be careful.
조심하세요.
I will help you.
내가 도와 줄게.
Bring this for him.
그를 위해 이것을 가져오세요.
Hang in there, madam.
조금만 참으세요, 부인.
It really hurts.
정말 아파요.
wait. Almost done.
기다리다. 거의 끝났다.
Hello, Young Master.
안녕하세요, 영마스터님.
- Young Master.
- 젊은 스승님.
let's do it.
하자.
Teacher, why are you doing that...
선생님 왜 그러세요...
are you okay. Customers are well taken care of...
괜찮아요. 손님들이 잘 보살펴지네요...
And they will be back as we speak.
그리고 우리가 말하는 동안 그들은 돌아올 것입니다 .
Young Master, please let Yinxing do it.
젊은 스승님, Yinxing이 하게 해주세요.
Not sure if I can do it?
내가 할 수 있을지 확신할 수 없나요?
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
It seems inappropriate to ask you to do this.
당신에게 이런 일을 시키는 것은 부적절해 보입니다 .
Young Master, how about you make me faint...
젊은 스승님, 저를 기절하게 만들어주시면 어떨까요...
Before treating the wound?
상처를 치료하기 전에?
Low pain tolerance.
통증에 대한 내성이 낮습니다.
Why are you protecting Hua Shen?
왜 Hua Shen을 보호하고 있습니까?
After all, he is my brother.
결국 그는 내 형제입니다.
Is it very fast? I am new...
매우 빠르나요? 나는 새롭다...
I kept hesitating...
계속 머뭇거렸는데...
But as you know, seniors need answers.
그런데 아시 다시피 선배님들은 답이 필요해요.
The teacher was very angry today.
선생님은 오늘 매우 화를 내셨습니다.
Young Master, aren’t you angry?
영스승님 화나지 않으셨나요?
Why should I be angry?
왜 화를 내야 합니까?
Why is Young Master helping me?
Young Master가 나를 돕는 이유는 무엇입니까?
You're not trying to test me, are you?
날 시험하려는 건 아니지?
You keep my secrets...
당신은 내 비밀을 유지합니다 ...
Save it.
저장해 두세요.
We are on the same side now.
우리는 지금 같은 편에 있습니다.
Is that person so boring...
그 사람이 너무 지루한 걸까요...
Until he has to say Who does he respect?
그가 말해야 할 때까지 그가 존경하는 사람은 누구인가?
great. I'm going.
좋아요. 나 간다.
ma'am.
부인.
When I went to the doctor to ask for medicine...
약을 달라고 의사에게 갔을 때 ..
I saw bodyguard Hua take out a medicine bottle...
경호원 후아가 약병을 꺼내는 걸 봤는데 ...
And then he hurried out.
그리고 서둘러 나갔다.
I said hello, but he didn't even notice me.
나는 인사했지만 그는 나를 알아차리지도 못했습니다.
I wonder what the wound is like.
상처는 어떤지 궁금하네요.
When you return...
당신이 돌아올 때...
I saw him standing at the door.
나는 그가 문 앞에 서 있는 것을 보았습니다.
Was he hurt too?
그 사람도 다쳤나요?
I do not know.
모르겠습니다.
I didn't look closely.
나는 자세히 보지 않았다.
I fell on a chair...
의자에 넘어졌는데...
And it was definitely scratched.
그리고 확실히 긁혔어요.
Tsuiju.
추이주.
Check out Huang Rongzhou.
Huang Rongzhou를 확인해 보세요.
What's the problem?
무슨 문제가 있나요?
Normally, I'm always happy...
평소에는 항상 행복해요...
Take the opportunity to access Rongzhou .
Rongzhou에 접근할 기회를 가지십시오 .
But not today.
그러나 오늘은 그렇지 않습니다.
Maybe he was worried about her.
아마도 그는 그녀를 걱정했을 것입니다.
Save your medicine.
약을 저장하십시오.
Madam, can you feel it...
부인, 느껴지시나요...
Does Young Master treat you differently?
Young Master가 당신을 다르게 대합니까?
Of course he treated me differently.
물론 그는 나를 다르게 대했습니다.
What will you do, wife?
부인은 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
You don't understand.
당신은 이해하지 않는다.
That person treats me like that...
그 사람이 날 그렇게 대하는데...
Because I know the secret.
왜냐하면 나는 그 비밀을 알고 있기 때문이다.
secret?
비밀?
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Secret. How should I say it?
비밀의. 어떻게 말해야 합니까?
Kian.
키안.
What does the teacher say?
선생님은 뭐라고 말씀하시나요?
I never had a chance to meet Mr. Lee.
나는 이 씨를 만날 기회가 없었다.
Yesterday, mom asked your dad.
어제 엄마가 네 아빠 한테 물어봤어.
They said Master sent your younger brother...
스승님께서 당신의 동생을 보내셨다고 하더군요...
Ke Yamen...
케 야멘...
above...
위에...
About that shameful behavior.
그 부끄러운 행동에 대해.
He can't interfere...
그 사람은 간섭할 수 없어...
When the incident comes to light.
사건이 밝혀지면.
So we need your help to learn more.
따라서 더 자세히 알아보려면 여러분의 도움이 필요합니다.
- I have a plan. - That's not enough.
- 난 계획을 가지고있어. - 그것은 충분하지 않아.
Your brother never suffered.
당신의 형제는 결코 고통받지 않았습니다.
How will he survive in prison?
그는 감옥에서 어떻게 살아남을 것인가?
How can he survive?
그는 어떻게 살아남을 수 있습니까?
I won't just sit still...
그냥 가만히 있지 않을게...
But we need to find the root cause of the problem...
하지만 문제의 근본 원인을 찾아야 하는데 ...
Before finding a solution.
해결책을 찾기 전에.
Mom isn't there...
엄마는 안 계시고...
Yesterday when he was taken away.
어제 그가 끌려갔을 때.
Why didn't you stop them?
왜 그들을 막지 않았나요?
He is your only brother.
그는 당신의 유일한 형제입니다.
When your mom was pregnant with you...
엄마가 너 임신했을 때...
I touch my mom's belly every day...
맨날 엄마 배 만지는데 ..
And he said he would protect you...
그리고 그 사람이 당신을 지켜준다고 하더군요...
After you were born.
당신이 태어난 후.
Now he's in trouble...
이제 그 사람이 곤경에 빠졌어요...
But are you just sitting here?
그런데 그냥 여기 앉아 계시나요?
Mother, don't worry.
어머니, 걱정하지 마세요.
If something truly unfair happened to my sister...
만약 내 여동생이 정말 억울한 일을 당했다면...
I won't stay still.
나는 가만히 있지 않을 것이다.
You have never been to prison.
당신은 감옥에 가본 적이 없습니다.
How do we know who framed him?
누가 그를 모함했는지 어떻게 알 수 있나요 ?
My mother asked Judge Wang for help...
엄마가 왕판사에게 도움을 요청했는데..
But he wouldn't let me in.
그러나 그는 나를 들여보내지 않았습니다.
He said his mother would be able to visit him in a few days.
그는 어머니가 며칠 후에 만 그를 방문할 수 있을 것이라고 말했습니다 .
How many more days?
며칠 더?
Your brother won't survive prison.
네 형은 감옥에서 살아남지 못할 거야 .
He will suffer.
그는 고통받을 것입니다.
What happened in this house...
이 집에서 일어난 일...
And you are Mr.'s wife.
그리고 당신은 Mr.의 아내이군요.
Mom feels...
엄마는 기분이...
The judge will not prevent you from entering.
판사는 귀하가 입장하는 것을 막지 않을 것입니다.
My brother was just taken...
내 동생이 방금 끌려갔어..
And I don't know yet...
그리고 아직은 모르겠어요...
What actually happened yesterday?
어제 실제로 무슨 일이 일어났는가.
What good will it do me if I go to jail now?
내가 지금 감옥에 간다고 무슨 소용이 있겠는가 ?
So what can you do while sitting here?
그럼 여기 앉아서 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
Mom knows...
엄마는 알아요...
You always think you're embarrassed...
넌 항상 형이 창피하다고 생각하는구나...
And it's not you who suffer in prison...
그리고 감옥에서 고통받는 것은 당신이 아닙니다 ...
Therefore, it is natural that you are not anxious.
그러므로 당신이 불안하지 않은 것은 당연합니다.
I think he's embarrassed?
내 생각엔 그 사람이 부끄러워하는 것 같아?
To be more precise, his inappropriate behavior was...
더 정확히 말하면 그의 부적절한 행동은...
It makes us feel ashamed.
그것은 우리를 부끄럽게 만듭니다.
It's true that I haven't been there yet.
아직 가보지 못한 게 사실이에요 .
But why be anxious?
그러나 불안해 하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Making a big fuss...
큰 소란을 피우고...
Before solving the problem...
문제를 해결하기 전에...
It only makes us vulnerable.
그것은 우리를 취약하게 만들 뿐입니다.
Mother, how can you be sure that he is innocent?
어머니, 그 사람이 결백하다고 어떻게 확신할 수 있나요 ?
Maybe he deserves it...
어쩌면 그 사람은 그럴 자격이 있을지도 몰라...
His current situation.
그의 현재 상황에 처해 있습니다.
Since I came here...
여기 온 이후로...
Mom can't stop talking...
엄마는 말을 멈추지 못해요...
How much my brother will suffer in prison.
내 동생이 감옥에서 얼마나 고통받을지.
Did you see that my hand was hurt?
내 손 다친 거 봤어?
And ask about it?
그리고 그것에 대해 물어봐?
- Mom... - That's it.
- 엄마... - 바로 그거예요.
My mother always takes my brother's side...
엄마는 항상 동생 편을 들어주는데...
And I got used to it.
그리고 나는 그것에 익숙해졌습니다.
If you don't get a proper answer from me...
나에게서 제대로 된 대답을 듣지 못한다면 ...
I don't think mom will let me go easily .
엄마가 쉽게 놔주지 않을 것 같아요 .
Now let's go to jail.
이제 감옥에 가자.
Find out who framed your sister .
누가 당신 여동생을 모함했는지 알아내세요 .
Madam, you said something hurtful
부인, 상처가 되는 말을 하셨습니다
I had too much trouble choosing my words carefully.
단어를 신중하게 선택하기에는 너무 고민이 많았습니다 .
First, let's get Shen out of jail.
먼저 Shen을 감옥에서 꺼내자 .
Pengadilan Yellow Blue
펜가딜란 황청
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
Kian.
키안.
Qian, I was waiting...
퀴안, 기다리고 있었어...
All day.
하루 종일.
Don't you understand what's going on?
현재 상황을 이해하지 못하시나요 ?
I worked really hard to get in here.
여기 들어오려고 엄청 노력했어요 .
My mother is not allowed in.
우리 어머니는 출입이 금지되어 있습니다.
Are you here to take me out? Isn't that right?
나를 꺼내려고 왔나요? 그렇지 않습니까?
It's not that easy, brother.
그렇게 쉬운 일이 아니군요, 형제님.
I've said it many times.
나는 그것을 여러 번 말했습니다.
Mu Yao is not someone you can touch.
Mu Yao는 당신이 만질 수 있는 사람이 아닙니다 .
Why don't you listen to me?
왜 내 말을 듣지 않는거야?
I remember everything you said.
나는 당신이 말한 모든 것을 기억합니다.
I won't touch anyone you tell me not to.
난 당신이 하지 말라고 한 사람은 건드리지 않을 거예요.
Why don't you trust me?
왜 나를 믿지 않습니까?
So what happened yesterday?
그럼 어제 무슨 일이 있었나요?
Why did I come to Mu Yao's room...
왜 무야오의 방에 오게 된 걸까요 ...
With dirty clothes?
지저분한 옷으로?
I really don't know.
나는 정말로 모른다.
I drank too much yesterday.
어제 너무 많이 마셨어요.
I tried to regain consciousness in the backyard.
나는 뒷마당에서 의식을 되찾으려고 노력했다.
One of your servants reminded me...
당신의 하인 중 하나가 나에게 상기시켰습니다...
To stay there.
거기 머물기 위해.
So I stayed in the pavilion.
그래서 나는 파빌리온에 머물렀다.
so?
그래서?
Then I...
그럼 내가...
Looks like you want to stay here...
여기 머물고 싶은 것 같던데 ...
A few more days.
며칠 더.
I will say
나는 말할 것이다.
I saw a beautiful maid in the backyard...
뒷마당에서 아름다운 하녀를 보았는데 ...
And he seduced me.
그리고 그는 나를 유혹했습니다.
I'm drunk...
난 취...
So I followed him somewhere.
그래서 나는 그를 어딘가로 따라갔습니다.
Soon after, I lost consciousness.
얼마 지나지 않아 나는 의식을 잃었습니다.
When I woke up, I saw you in front of me.
잠에서 깨어났을 때 내 앞에 당신이 보였습니다.
I'm so scared I can't speak. me...
너무 무서워서 말을 할 수가 없어요. 나...
Are you sure the maid seduced you?
하녀가 당신을 유혹한 게 확실해요?
He kept spying on me.
그는 나를 계속해서 엿보았다.
Doesn't that mean he likes me?
그 사람이 나를 좋아한다는 뜻 아닌가요?
You are so confident!
당신은 너무 자신감이 있어요!
I drank too much alcohol...
술을 너무 많이 마셨어...
And act according to your physical desires.
그리고 육체적 욕망에 따라 행동하십시오.
But you excuse yourself.
그러나 당신은 스스로 변명합니다.
No one can control themselves when they are drunk.
술에 취하면 누구도 자신을 통제할 수 없습니다 .
I think my assessment is correct...
내 평가는 맞는 것 같은데...
Affected by excessive alcohol.
과도한 알코올의 영향을 받습니다.
So I think he's interested in me...
그래서 그 사람이 나한테 관심이 있는 것 같은데...
And I broke in by mistake ...
그리고 실수로 침입했는데...
To someone's residence...
누군가의 거주지로...
And it looks like a pervert.
그리고 변태로 보이죠.
Qian, it's not my fault.
퀴안, 내 잘못이 아니야.
You said it with conviction.
당신은 그것을 확신에 차서 말했습니다 .
It looks okay...
괜찮아 보이는데...
Although our mothers say it differently.
우리 엄마들은 다르게 말하지만.
In that case...
그 경우에는...
Stay here and repent for a few more days.
여기에 머물면서 며칠만 더 회개하십시오.
Kian.
키안.
Save me, Chen.
구해줘, 첸.
This place is dirty and smells really bad.
이곳은 더럽고 냄새가 너무 심해요.
There are also rats.
쥐도 있습니다.
The guards tortured me.
교도관들이 나를 고문했어요.
I don't think I can last a few more days .
며칠 더 버틸 수 없을 것 같아요 .
Kian.
키안.
Is it true?
사실인가요?
A wound on my head...
머리에 상처가...
It healed well.
잘 치료되었습니다.
I don't think you were tortured.
고문을 당한 것 같지는 않습니다.
- I... - Learn from this.
- 난... - 이것부터 배워요.
Kian!
키안!
Kian.
키안.
How is your sister?
언니는 잘 지내요?
I warned him many times...
나는 그에게 여러 번 경고했습니다 ...
But his physical desires...
하지만 그의 육체적 욕망은...
Always master.
항상 마스터하세요.
This time...
이 시간...
He even did that in your house.
그는 심지어 당신 집에서도 그런 일을 했습니다.
He deserves to be beaten.
그는 구타당할 자격이 있습니다.
You think too...
당신도 생각하는데...
Is that person the criminal?
그 사람이 범인인가요?
Kian.
키안.
your sister...
당신의 자매...
It's quite immoral...
상당히 부도덕한데...
But that person did...
그런데 그 사람이 그랬어요...
Because he was drunk.
왜냐하면 그는 술에 취했기 때문입니다.
That person is my only son...
그 사람은 내 하나뿐인 아들인데...
And you only have one brother.
그리고 당신에게는 형제가 한 명뿐입니다.
Even if you get angry at me...
나한테 화를 내더라도...
You can't leave him in trouble .
그를 곤경에 빠뜨릴 수는 없습니다 .
my beloved daughter
내 사랑하는 딸.
Why should I be angry?
왜 화를 내야 합니까?
I don't think he did that.
나는 그가 그랬다고 생각하지 않습니다.
Is it true?
사실인가요?
Hello, madam.
안녕하세요, 부인.
You are my servant. No format required.
당신은 나의 하인입니다. 형식이 필요하지 않습니다.
I have a few questions .
몇 가지 질문이 있습니다 .
Have you seen anything strange...?
혹시 이상한거 보셨나요...?
The day you went to look for my sister?
네가 내 동생을 찾으러 갔던 날?
I went to the backyard...
뒷마당에 갔더니..
Muda Hua was sitting alone...
Muda Hua는 혼자 앉아있었습니다 ...
In the pavilion.
파빌리온에서.
They say the servant left...
하인이 떠났다고 하는데...
Buy him some hangover soup.
그에게 숙취 수프를 사주세요.
What he said was...
그가 말한 것은 ...
After I deliver my message?
내 메시지를 전달한 후에요?
He said he drank too much...
술을 너무 많이 마셨다고 하더군요...
And I want to rest there.
그리고 그곳에서 쉬고 싶다.
He asked me to tell Mrs. Hua...
그는 나에게 Hua 부인에게 말해달라고 요청했습니다 ...
Coming to the pavilion to look for him...
그를 찾으러 파빌리온에 오다니 ...
After the banquet was over.
연회가 끝난 후.
Who did you tell that he was in the pavilion?
그 사람이 파빌리온에 있었다고 누구한테 말했나요 ?
no.
아니요.
Did you meet someone on your way home?
집에 가는 길에 누군가를 만났나요 ?
I haven't met anyone.
나는 누구도 만나지 않았습니다.
ma'am.
부인.
What did I do wrong?
내가 뭐 잘못 했어요?
It has nothing to do with you.
당신과는 아무 상관이 없습니다.
Don't think too much about it. Go and rest.
그것에 대해 너무 많이 생각하지 마십시오. 가서 쉬세요.
Madam, what is Cuizhu doing?
부인, Cuizhu는 무엇을 하고 있나요?
There is nothing. I'm just sure...
아무것도 없습니다. 난 단지 확신하고 있을 뿐인데...
To make myself calm.
나 자신을 차분하게 만들기 위해서.
Where does Mu Yao live now?
무야오는 지금 어디에 살고 있나요?
same as before...
이전과 동일...
But it has been renovated.
하지만 개조되었습니다.
good.
좋은.
ma'am.
부인.
The teacher got angry last time...
저번에 선생님이 화를 내셨는데...
So he's a bit over the top.
그래서 그는 약간 정상에 있습니다.
You may have suffered serious injuries.
당신은 심각한 부상을 입었을 것입니다.
You don't have to be awake.
깨어 있을 필요는 없습니다.
Go back to your room and rest.
방으로 돌아가서 휴식을 취하세요.
I'm doing great.
잘 지내요.
What are you guys doing?
너희들 뭐하는거야?
ma'am.
부인.
The Lord has commanded us to take care...
주님께서 우리에게 돌보라고 명하셨는데...
Your concubine's residence.
귀하의 첩의 거주지.
No one can enter.
아무나 들어갈 수 없습니다.
you...
너...
Please tell Mu Yao that I am coming. He will let me in.
Mu Yao에게 내가 간다고 전해주세요. 그는 나를 들여보낼 것이다.
Please, ma'am.
부탁드립니다, 부인.
Please wait outside.
밖에서 기다리세요.
Okay, ma'am.
알겠습니다, 부인.
You were waiting for me, right?
당신은 나를 기다리고 있었죠, 그렇죠?
If you come to defend Hua Shen...
Hua Shen을 방어하러 온다면 ...
Shouldn’t we be humble?
겸손해야 하지 않겠습니까?
My brother is innocent.
내 동생은 결백해요.
Why should I defend him?
내가 왜 그를 변호해야 합니까?
Mu Yao, it's just the two of us now.
Mu Yao, 이제 우리 둘뿐이에요.
Let’s get straight to the point.
바로 요점을 살펴보겠습니다.
I think...
제 생각에는...
I wouldn't use such a cunning method ...
그런 교활한 방법은 쓰지 않을 텐데 ...
After being locked up before.
전에 갇혀 있던 후.
I realized I was wrong.
나는 내가 틀렸다는 것을 깨달았습니다.
I'm really disappointed.
정말 실망스럽네요.
I didn't mean to come here...
여기 올 생각은 아니었는데...
But I think I have to do my part...
하지만 내 역할은 해야 한다고 생각해요 ...
In your play...
당신의 연극에서...
Don't let your hard work go to waste.
여러분의 노고가 헛되지 않도록.
I told you I wouldn't compete with you anymore...
더 이상 너랑 경쟁 안 할 거라고 말했잖아 ...
Demi Jong-ye is...
데미 종예란...
But you don't believe me.
하지만 당신은 나를 믿지 않습니다.
You even used a cunning method...
교활한 방법까지 사용하셨군요...
And used it to get rid of me.
그리고 나를 없애기 위해 그것을 사용했습니다.
Do you think I'm doing this for him?
내가 그 사람을 위해서 이러는 것 같아?
What else?
또 뭐야?
You framed Hua Shen.
당신은 Hua Shen을 모함했습니다.
This time I won't stand still.
이번에는 가만히 있지 않겠습니다.
Every injustice has a perpetrator.
모든 불의에는 가해자가 있습니다.
I am patient with you...
나는 당신에게 인내심을 가지고 있습니다 ...
Because I regret what I did to you.
내가 당신에게 한 일을 후회하기 때문입니다.
But now you're implicating innocent people...
하지만 지금 당신은 무고한 사람들을 연루시키고 있습니다...
Using cunning means.
교활한 수단을 사용하여.
I will never be generous again.
나는 다시는 관대하지 않을 것이다.
Every injustice has a perpetrator.
모든 불의에는 가해자가 있습니다.
Hua Chen.
화첸.
How dare you say that?
감히 그런 말을 합니까?
Why can't I say that ?
나는 왜 그렇게 말할 수 없습니까 ?
Tuan.
투안.
Judge Wang sent more people.
왕 판사는 더 많은 사람을 보냈습니다.
This is related to the Hua Shen incident.
이것은 Hua Shen 사건과 관련이 있습니다.
They want to ask Mu-cheop a question.
그들은 무첩에게 질문하고 싶어합니다.
Should we make them wait outside like before?
예전처럼 밖에서 기다리게 해야 할까요 ?
Let it wait.
기다리게 놔두세요.
All right.
알겠습니다.
wait.
기다리다.
Let me ask you first.
먼저 물어보겠습니다.
Your family are selfish people...
너희 가족은 이기적인 사람들이구나...
A person who cannot distinguish between right and wrong.
옳고 그름을 구별하지 못하는 사람 .
You said Hua Shen was innocent, right?
Hua Shen이 결백하다고 했죠?
You were the one who prepared the banquet incident, right?
연회 사건을 준비한 사람이 바로 당신이었지요 ?
I really question my brother's morality...
내 동생의 도덕성이 정말 의심스럽습니다...
But he never...
하지만 그는 결코...
You have bad intentions.
당신에게 나쁜 의도가 있습니다.
Is it true?
사실인가요?
I can't guarantee anything else, but...
다른 건 보장 할 수 없지만 ...
I can tell you that he has never lied to me.
나는 그가 나에게 거짓말을 한 적이 없다고 말할 수 있습니다.
I warned him many times ...
나는 그에게 여러 번 경고했습니다 ...
And he always respected my requests.
그리고 그는 항상 내 요청을 존중했습니다.
In the end, you...
결국, 당신은 ...
I have known you for a long time.
나는 당신을 오랫동안 알고 있었습니다.
You are a person who does not shed tears easily .
당신은 쉽게 눈물을 흘리지 않는 사람이에요 .
That day, you were curled up in the corner of your room...
그날 당신은 방구석에 웅크리고 있었습니다...
Trembling with fear.
두려움에 떨면서.
It's just acting.
그냥 연기일 뿐입니다.
Your intentions are clear.
당신의 의도는 분명합니다.
You are right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
I locked him up.
나는 그를 가두었다.
Hua Shen didn't touch me at all .
Hua Shen은 나를 전혀 건드리지 않았습니다 .
I heard the news that the servant died...
하인이 죽었다는 소식을 들었는데...
A few days ago at Hua Residence...
며칠 전 후아 레지던스에서..
But Mr. Hwa appeared at the banquet...
그런데 연회에 화선생이 나타났는데...
Without any indication of the outcome.
결과에 대한 어떠한 표시도 없이.
Head Servant Hwa acts as a shield for the family.
헤드 서번트 화는 가족의 방패 역할을 합니다.
Of course you guys aren't there...
당연하지 너희들은 거기 없어...
Who cares about the life of a servant?
하인의 생명을 누가 걱정합니까?
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Waiter commits suicide
자살한 웨이터..
This is Linglong.
링롱이에요.
Your father told us to buy this.
너희 아버지가 우리에게 이것을 사라고 하셨다.
The young lady has reached marriageable age.
아가씨는 결혼 적령기가 되었습니다..
So you need to get dressed.
그러니 옷을 입어야 합니다.
Look at the jewels.
보석을보세요.
Very beautiful.
매우 아름답습니다.
do you like
너는 좋아한다?
I'll give it to you.
내가 그걸 너에게 줄게.
I am a waiter.
나는 웨이터입니다.
How can I use this precious thing?
이 귀중한 것을 어떻게 사용할 수 있습니까 ?
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
This one.
이 하나.
That's inappropriate.
그건 부적절해요.
Put it in.
에 넣어.
It's right for you.
당신에게 적합합니다.
He said he had reached marriageable age.
결혼 적령기에 이르렀다고 하셨어요 ..
But you are one year older than me.
그런데 당신은 나보다 한 살 더 많아요.
This hairpin will be your dowry.
이 머리핀이 당신의 지참금이 될 거예요.
dowry?
결혼 지참금?
Nona...
노나...
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
It won't run.
실행되지 않습니다.
Linglong lost his parents when he was young...
링롱은 어렸을 때 부모를 잃었습니다 ...
And he grew up with me in the North.
그리고 북쪽에서 나와 함께 자랐습니다.
You remember him, right?
당신은 그를 기억하지, 그렇지?
Some are more beautiful.
일부는 더 아름답습니다.
Go ahead and try it. Cheers.
어서 해봐요. 건배.
The servant was once a criminal.
그 하인은 한때 범죄자였습니다.
He is an orphan...
그는 고아입니다 ...
And I have no family.
그리고 가족도 없어요.
My father was scolded...
아버지가 욕을 먹었어요...
Stealing property...
재산을 훔치고..
And isolated.
그리고 고립되었습니다.
All the servants in my house...
우리 집에 있는 모든 하인들...
For sale.
판매용.
Still a slave...
아직도 노예야...
Wherever it is sold.
판매되는 곳마다.
At first I thought so too.
처음에는 나도 그렇게 생각했다.
but...
하지만...
Why Hua Shen...
왜 Hua Shen이어야 하는가...
Who bought it?
누가 샀나요?
dare!
감히!
- You will beat me! - Hwa sister...
- 당신은 나를 이길 것입니다! - 화 언니...
Stop...
멈추다...
I pity him.
나는 그를 불쌍히 여긴다.
How ungrateful.
얼마나 배은망덕한지요.
You should thank your lucky stars...
행운의 별들에게 감사해야 합니다 ...
Because my friend likes you.
내 친구가 당신을 좋아하기 때문이죠.
How dare you refuse...
감히 거절을 하다니...
Did you even hit Huang?
심지어 황을 때렸나요?
Who do you think you are?
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까?
I was wrong.
나는 틀렸다.
I'm sorry, husband.
미안해요, 남편.
Are you my concubine?
당신이 내 첩이에요?
My concubine?
내 첩?
I don't consider you my concubine.
나는 당신을 내 첩으로 생각하지 않습니다.
You lowly slave...
하찮은 노예야...
And I bought you!
그리고 나는 당신을 샀습니다!
You get angry easily, don't you?
당신은 쉽게 화를 내는군요, 그렇죠?
good. I am a good person...
좋은. 나는 좋은 사람이다...
Well, I'll leave it to you this time.
그럼 이번에는 남겨두겠습니다.
Now pack your bags...
이제 짐을 싸세요...
And go with Tuan Wang.
그리고 Tuan Wang과 함께 가십시오.
Can you hear me?
내 말 들리나요?
my husband...
내 남편...
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
I mean, from now on you are mine.
내 말은, 이제부터 당신은 내 것입니다.
It really is.
정말 그렇습니다.
my husband.
내 남편.
A woman cannot serve two husbands.
여자는 두 남편을 섬길 수 없습니다.
How can you hand me over?
어떻게 나를 넘겨줄 수 있나요?
Who do you think you are?
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까?
You are just a lowly servant!
당신은 하찮은 하인일 뿐입니다!
I can hand you over to anyone!
누구에게나 당신을 넘겨줄 수 있어요 !
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
My home is like his home.
내 집은 그의 집과 같습니다.
I will treat you well.
나는 당신을 잘 대할 것입니다.
If you don't want to, that's okay.
원하지 않는다면 괜찮습니다.
Take this. I'll sell you to a brothel!
이것을 가져가세요. 널 매춘업소에 팔아버릴 거야!
Do you want me to do that?
내가 그렇게 하길 바라나요?
Oh no.
아요.
Even though I'm a slave...
노예인데도..
I can't stand such humiliation !
나는 그런 굴욕을 참을 수 없습니다 !
Selir Linglong.
셀리르 링롱.
Selir Linglong!
셀리르 링롱!
so...
그래서...
Hua Chen...
화첸...
What makes you confident?
무엇이 당신을 확신하게 합니까?
Hua Shen is innocent?
Hua Shen이 결백하다고요?
Insignificant servant...
하찮은 하인...
The person who died in Hwataek...
화택에서 죽은 사람은...
The person I consider my older brother.
내가 형이라고 생각하는 사람 .
- I... - What?
- 난... - 뭐?
What do you want to say?
말하고 싶은게 뭡니까?
Hua Chen.
화첸.
I'm giving you a chance. I'm giving you time.
나는 당신에게 기회를 주고 있다. 나는 당신에게 시간을 주고 있다.
But what do you do?
그러나 당신은 무엇을 합니까?
As you know...
아시다시피...
Linglong and I are very close.
Linglong과 나는 매우 친합니다.
Do you think you made up for it?
당신은 그것을 보상했다고 생각합니까?
By making me Jong Ye-ran's concubine?
나를 종예란의 첩 으로 만들어서 ?
I didn't know that the maid was Linglong ...
그 가정부가 링롱인 줄은 몰랐어요 ...
I also ask your Excellency...
저도 각하께 부탁드립니다...
Do you consider yourself an ordinary servant?
평범한 하인이라고 생각하시나요?
So please be quiet...
그러니까 조용히 좀 하세요...
And will you hand over Hua Shen to your father?
그리고 Hua Shen을 아버지에게 넘겨 주시겠습니까 ?
You know Steward Hu will protect him...
후아 청지기가 그를 보호할 거라는 걸 알잖아요...
But you're still doing that.
그런데 아직도 그러고 계시네요.
The reason is in your eyes...
그 이유는 당신의 눈에...
The life of an anonymous server is very precious.
익명 서버의 생명은 매우 귀중합니다.
You said you'd never hurt me again...
다시는 나에게 상처를 주지 않겠다고 했잖아 ...
And I almost believed you.
그리고 나는 당신을 거의 믿었습니다.
I want to believe it...
나는 그것을 믿고 싶다 ...
You may not be involved in our family's affairs.
당신은 우리 가족의 사건에 관여하지 않을 수도 있습니다 .
But what happened to Linglong...
그런데 링롱에게 무슨 일이 있었던 걸까요...
I realized I will never forgive you .
나는 결코 당신을 용서하지 않을 것임을 깨달았습니다 .
Many people are having difficulties...
많은 분들이 어려움을 겪고 계십니다..
In the hands of the Hua family...
Hua 가문의 손에...
And it doesn't come true.
그리고 그것은 실현되지 않습니다.
You are part of the Hua family.
당신은 Hua 가족의 일원입니다.
It makes you indifferent and selfish.
그것은 당신을 무관심하고 이기적으로 만듭니다.
You can pretend not to know...
모르는 척 해도 되는데...
Because I didn't see it...
못 봤으니까...
But I can't.
하지만 나는 못해.
So you framed him?
그래서 그 사람을 모함한 거야?
To avenge Linglong?
링롱의 복수를 하려고?
Because you didn't punish him...
당신이 그 사람을 처벌하지 않았기 때문에 ...
I made sure he got his reward.
나는 그 사람이 보상을 받도록 만들었습니다.
You are not interested in the lives of your servants.
당신은 하인의 삶에 관심이 없습니다 .
What about me, Concubine Jong Ye?
나는 어떻습니까, 첩 종예란?
Could it cost him a fortune?
그에게 막대한 비용이 들 수 있을까요 ?
By doing this?
이렇게 해서?
Do you take advantage of a man who loves you?
당신을 사랑하는 남자를 이용합니까?
Why can't I do that?
나는 왜 그렇게 할 수 없습니까?
That means we must accept all evil ...
즉, 우리는 모든 악을 받아들여야 한다는 뜻입니다 ...
What the Hwa family did...
화씨 가족이 한 일은...
Without a fight?
싸움도 없이?
For me...
나를 위한...
As long as you're against family...
가족에 반대하는 한...
It is merely a means to an end.
그것은 단지 목적을 위한 수단일 뿐입니다.
great.
좋아요.
I understand.
이해합니다.
ma'am.
부인.
Madam, what's going on?
부인, 무슨 일이에요?
am...
이다...
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
From now on, without my permission...
이제부터 내 허락 없이...
You cannot enter Yao 's house .
야오의 집 에는 들어갈 수 없습니다 .
If Muda Muda doesn't stop you that day ...
그날 Muda Muda가 당신을 막지 않는다면...
Will your sword cut me down?
당신의 칼이 나를 베겠습니까?
It's true, right?
사실이지?
Jong Ye-ran.
종예란.
Are jade pendants that important?
옥 펜던트가 그렇게 중요한가요?
Does it really matter who that person is?
그 사람이 누구인지가 정말 중요할까요?
Who is standing with you in the temple?
성전에서 너희와 함께 서 있는 사람은 누구인가?
When you were young?
어렸을 때요?
Are romantic feelings possible ?
낭만적인 감정이 가능할까요 ?
Just remembering someone ...
누군가를 기억하는 것만으로도 ...
The person you gave the jade pendant to?
당신이 옥 펜던트를 준 사람?
Why am I saying this now?
왜 지금 이런 말을 하는 걸까요?
Just curious...
그냥 궁금해서...
Is it true that he is a liar?
거짓말쟁이라는게 사실인가요...
You can't gain someone else's trust...
다른 사람의 신뢰를 얻을 수 없습니다 ...
And improve the situation.
그리고 상황을 개선하십시오.
Even if you sacrifice your life...
목숨을 바쳐 도 ...
I didn't even have time to defend myself...
방어할 시간도 없었는데...
When you draw a sword on me .
당신이 나에게 칼을 뽑을 때 .
Am I showing weakness...
약한 모습을 보이고 있는 걸까요...
Are you trying to manipulate me into freeing Hua Shen?
나를 조종해서 Hua Shen을 풀어주려고요?
great...
좋아요...
If you think that way about me too.
당신도 나에 대해 그렇게 생각한다면.
ma'am.
부인.
Dia menyukai Qianzhi.
Dia menyukai Qianzhi.
What are you going to do with Hua Shen?
Hua Shen을 어떻게 할 건가요 ?
I leave it to you.
당신에게 맡깁니다.
Tuan.
투안.
King Hakim's men have not left yet.
왕하킴님의 부하들은 아직 떠나지 않았습니다.
What should I say to them this time?
이번에는 그들에게 무슨 말을 해야 할까요 ?
Find the reason and kick them out.
이유를 찾아 쫓아내세요.
All right.
알겠습니다.
Adigan Bonus
애디건 보너스
Internal damage appears to be serious.
내부 손상이 심각한 것 같습니다 .
Why do I only want Jindao powder?
왜 진다오 파우더만 원하는 걸까요?
I'll check it.
내가 체크해 볼게.
Don't bother. Just give me Jindao powder.
귀찮게하지 마십시오. 그냥 진다오 가루 주세요.
hurry up, please.
서둘러주세요.
But, you don't seem to experience...
하지만, 당신은 경험하지 못하는 것 같습니다 ...
external wounds.
외부 상처.
Jindao powder is only good for external wounds.
진다오 분말은 외부 상처 에만 좋습니다 .
Haven't found it yet?
아직 찾지 못하셨나요?
I am looking for it.
나는 그것을 찾고 있다.
this. Where is the pain?
이것. 고통은 어디에 있습니까?
We will treat your wounds.
상처를 치료해 드리겠습니다.
Why are you in a hurry?
왜 서두르나요?
Doctor, do you have Jindao powder?
박사님, 진다오 가루 있어요?
What happen? Who got hurt?
무슨 일이에요? 누가 다쳤나요?
Why does everyone want Jin Dao powder?
왜 모두가 진다오 파우더를 원하는 걸까요?
please give it to me This is an emergency situation.
나에게 주세요. 이것은 긴급 상황입니다.